Qasim Hassan Khan

0334-2638493 kukugem@yahoo.com http://www.templates.stillidea.net/gasim

About Me: I am UI/UX developer and designer with experience of more than 7 years. I started my career in Multan and worked for different software houses there, and currently I am located & working in Lahore for more than one year as a senior UI/UX developer in SWI. I have been also working for the international market place Envato (http://market.envato.com/) for more than 5 years as an author on themeforest.net (http://themeforest.net/). I have more than 60 approved items there. You can check my work on my online portfolio in the link given at the top. I primarily consider myself a UI/UX developer, but I can design web layouts PSD's too as working for themeforest has taught me the typographic sense, using the eye catching colors and utilization of white spaces in the design. So, that's make me an independent UI/UX resource who can design and convert it into HTML.

Religion - Islam City - Lahore Nationality - Pakistani Date of Birth - 25th-March-1991 Marital Status - Married

Education:

Fauji Foundation Model School [Hyderabad, Pakistan]Matriculation (Computers) – **72%**2006

College of Excellence for Boys [Hyderabad, Pakistan] Intermediate (Pre Engineering) – 58% 2008

IMSA (Institute of Modern Sciences & Arts) [Hyderabad, Pakistan] BCIT – **2.9 G. P** 2012

Experience:

Sublime Wireless Incorporate(SWI) [Lahore, Pakistan] Senior UI/UX Engineer Nov 2017 – present (1.5 Years)

Responsibilities:

- Translation of the UI/UX design wireframes to actual code that will produce visual elements of the application
- Designing UI/UX and bridge the gap between graphical design and technical implementation
- Develop new user-facing features
- Build reusable code and libraries for future use
- Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs
- Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability
- Paint The HTML Structure Using Provided JSON by backend developers
- Assure that all user input is validated before submitting to back-end
- Collaborate with other team members and stakeholders

Sound View Technologies [Lahore, Pakistan] Front-End Developer (Part Time) Aug 2018 – present (06 Months)

Responsibilities:

- Develop new user-facing features
- Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs
- Paint The HTML Structure Using Provided JSON by backend developers
- Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability

Systons [Multan, Pakistan] Senior Web Designer and Developer Nov 2016 – Oct 2017 (01 Year)

Responsibilities:

- Design PSD layout for themeforest.net
- Convert PSD into HTML for themeforest.net
- Train the juniors and lead the team
- Manage projects and updates

Sugotech [Multan, Pakistan] Senior Web Developer January 2013 – April 2016 (03 Year)

Responsibilities:

- Design PSD layout for themeforest.net
- Convert PSD into HTML for themeforest.net
- Train the juniors and lead the team
- Manage projects and updates

Next Syntax Technologies [Multan, Pakistan] Assistant Web Developer January 2012 – Jan 2013 (01 Year)

Responsibilities:

- Css Customization of Wordpress Website
- Perform assigned task related to CSS
- Learn new techniques

True Educators School [Hyderabad, Pakistan] Computer Lab In charge, Teacher August 2010 – August 2011 (01 Year)

Responsibilities:

- Update and maintain the computer lab
- Teaching Math and Computer
- Taking part in admin related issues

Sindh Grammar School [Hyderabad, Pakistan] Receptionist, Teacher August 2008 – August 2010 (02 Year)

Responsibilities:

- Front Desk Officer
- Teaching Math and Computer
- Taking part in admin related issues

Technologies:

- 1. HTML (Expert)
- 2. CSS (Expert)
- 3. PSD (Professional)
- 4. Vanilla JS/ JavaScript (Professional)
- 5. JQuery (Professional)
- 6. Ajax (Professional)
- 7. WordPress (Professional)

Frameworks:

- 1. Angular JS (Professional)
- 2. Angular 7 (Beginner)
- 3. Bootstrap (Expert)
- 4. Materialize (Expert)

Tools:

- 1. Photoshop CS6, CC
- 2. Visual Studio (TFS)
- 3. Atom
- 4. Sublime Text

My Specialties:

- 1. Pixel Perfect Coding
- 2. Well Commented Code
- 3. Super Responsiveness
- 4. Shortest Possible and flexible coding
- 5. Professional Designing Skills
- 6. Know the usage of fonts, colors and images in a design
- 7. Good Organizational Behavior
- 8. Punctual
- 9. Restricted to deadline.

Certifications:

- 1. English Language Course [Aptech, Hyderabad] [2006]
- 2. Android Development Course [The Net Rider, Multan] [2015]

Languages:

- 1. English
- 2. Urdu